# **Niall Martin CV**

**Home Address:** Mullantlavan, Magheracloone, Carrickmacross, Co. Monaghan **Phone:** 087 9867024 **Email:** <a href="mailto:business@niallmartin.com">business@niallmartin.com</a> **Website:** niallmartin.com

#### **Personal Profile**

23-year-old Computer Science & Information Technology graduate from NUI Galway. Have experience the C# Java, C, JavaScript, SQL, and HTML programming languages. Have a particular interest working with .NET technologies. Am currently looking for work as a software engineer.

#### Education

# Sept 2012 – June 2016: Bachelor of Science (Computer Science and Information Technology), National University of Ireland, Galway

- ➤ Graduated with Upper 2<sup>nd</sup> Class Honours (2:1)
- > Topics covered include:
  - Distributed Systems & Co Operative Computing
  - Software Engineering
  - Real Time Systems
  - Artificial Intelligence
  - Advanced Professional Skills
  - Machine Learning & Data Mining
  - Graphics & Image Process
  - Modern Information Management
  - Computer Security and Forensic Computing
  - Systems Modelling and Simulation
  - A final year project (Athletics Management web app, detailed below)

#### **Competed Projects**

(Source code for these projects are available at https://github.com/NiallFMartin)

- ➤ <u>A fully featured Athletics Management web application</u>. Developed using ASP.NET MVC and Entity Framework. Written in C#. Includes the following features:
- Performance data logging saved to an external Microsoft SQL database.
- Trend analysis of athletes' performance throughout the year
- Generation of set performance goals determined by the athlete's existing results
- Comparison of athletes' key performance data for squad selection
- ➤ <u>Java RMI based Exam System</u>. Project consisted of a client-server model where a student (client) could download an assessment object from the server, complete the assessment and then upload is back to the server for correction.
- ➤ <u>Information Retrieval System</u>. Developed an Information Retrieval System written in C# from scratch. Given a query, it computes the Cosine Similarity between the query and a number of documents, and returns a ranked list of all relevant documents relating to that query using a modern weighting scheme (TFIDF).
- Personal Website. Developed using ASP.NET MVC and written in C# and razor HTML. Viewable at niallmartin.com

- A fully functioning instant Chat messaging server with register/ login functionality, as well as the ability to privately message other users. (created for a group assignment using Node.js and HTML)
- > A fully functioning Space Invaders game (created using Java). Included rounds and saved high score.

# Sept 2006 - June 2012: Leaving Certificate, Patrician High School, Carrickmacross, Co. Monaghan

• Achieved 485 points (Including 25 bonus points for Higher level maths with the following grades: Mathematics(Higher): B1 English(Higher): B3 Physics(Higher): B2 Geography(Higher): B3 Biology(Higher): B1 French(Higher): C3 Irish(Ordinary): A2

### **Employment History**

# April 2015 – September 2015, Intern Software Engineer, Storm Technology Ltd.

- ➤ Was a member of a team developing an internal work management system. Developed using C#, was an ASP.NET MVC application to give complete project and resource breakdowns.
- ➤ Tester for the new Bus Éireann website booking system. Created and ran test cases using Microsoft test manager. System now released at <a href="http://www.buseireann.ie/">http://www.buseireann.ie/</a>

# June 2014 - September 2014, Human Resources Member, Monaghan Mushrooms Group

- ➤ Helped in launch of new TMS(Time Management System) on UK Monaghan Mushrooms sites.
- Organised interviews for long term sick employees. Assisted in facilitating requests from claim solicitors for employees filing claims

### May 2013 - September 2013, Human Resources Member, Monaghan Mushrooms Group

- Assisted in, and later was administrator for employee fingerprint scanning system (Adding new employees, removing past employees, etc.)
- ➤ Took part in employee recruitment process (replying to applications, setting up interviews, etc.) Assisted in the employee salary payment process (sending out cheques, added banking details for new employees)
- Completely reorganised the department file room.

# June 2012 - September 2012, Information Technology Worker, Monaghan Mushrooms Group Duties:

- Implemented new Asset tagging and management system throughout various Monaghan Mushrooms sites.
- Helped introduce and implement new system that distributed employee payslips via email. (worked in collaboration with HR department and other members in IT)
- Administered general IT support to Monaghan Mushrooms employees.

#### **Skills Profile & Personal Endeavours**

- ➤ Have experience in the C# Java, JavaScript, HTML, C, and SQL programming languages. I have used these to good effect in a number of academic and personal projects (some of which were mentioned earlier). I am also constantly looking at new technologies to learn and implement.
- Have developed a personal website at niallmartin.com.
- ➤ Have gained proficiency in my communication skills, though my work in Software engineering, IT support and Human resources.

- ➤ Have lived and worked on a sheep farm for my entire life, and am no stranger to manual labour.
- Hold a full driving license.
- ➤ Hold two all-Ireland U18 interzone winners medals in indoor bowls, as well as qualifying for the All-Ireland open singles tournament in 2014, and playing in the World masters in 2013 and 2014.

### **Interests & Hobbies**

- Gaelic football Played on various underage teams with my local club (Magheracloone GFC) and would still follow their progress closely. Am also an avid fan of the Monaghan team.
- Indoor bowls Play with my local club Magheracloone, and compete in many open tournaments.

# **References**

Name: Denis Cronin

**Position:** Delivery Lead in Storm Technology Ltd. **Relationship to me:** Supervisor during my internship

Email: dcronin@storm.ie

Name: Dr. Michael Schukat

Position: Lecturer in Department of Information Technology at NUI Galway

Relationship to me: Final Year Project Supervisor

Phone: 091 492031 Email: michael.schukat@nuigalway.ie